They hunt to live. It lives to hunt.
Prey is a thriller, action, science fiction film directed by Dan Trachtenberg.
When danger threatens her camp, the fierce and highly skilled
Comanche warrior Naru sets out to protect her people.
But the prey she stalks turns out to be a highly evolved alien
predator with a technically advanced arsenal.
Naru, played by Amber Midthunder.
Taabe, played by Dakota Beavers.
Aruka, played by Michelle Thrush.
Wasape, played by Stormee Kipp.
Chief Kehetu, played by Julian Black Antelope.
Predator, played by Dane DiLiegro.
Prey is a 2022 American science fiction action horror film directed by Dan Trachtenberg from
a screenplay by Patrick Aison, based on a story by Aison and Trachtenberg.
It is the fifth installment in the Predator film series.
The story takes place chronologically before the previous films,
as it is set in the Northern Great Plains in 1719.
It stars Amber Midthunder, Dakota Beavers, Dane DiLiegro, Michelle Thrush,
Stormee Kipp, Julian Black Antelope, and Bennett Taylor.
The story revolves around a young Comanche woman, Naru, who
is striving to prove herself as a hunter.
She finds herself having to protect her people from a vicious,
humanoid alien that hunts humans for sport.
Development of the film began during the production of The Predator (2018), when producer John Davis was
approached by Trachtenberg and Aison, with a concept that they had been developing since 2016.
In late 2020, the film's title was revealed.
Principal photography took place around Calgary during the summer of 2021, with most of the film
being filmed in English, with some sequences being shot in Comanche and French as well.
A full Comanche language dub was provided for the film, with the cast reprising
their roles, thus making it the first feature film to do so.
Prey premiered at San Diego Comic-Con on July 21, 2022, and was released by 20th
Century Studios as a Hulu original film in the United States on August 5.
The film received positive reviews from critics and high viewership, leading Trachtenberg to direct two
additional Predator films, Predator: Killer of Killers and Predator: Badlands, both released in 2025.
The film explores themes of hunter, native
american, alien life-form, alien, prequel.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.